const questions = [
  {
    "question": "An aircraft is 100 NM from a VOR facility. Assuming no error when using a deviation indicator where 1 dot = 2\u00b0 deviation, how many dots deviation from the centre line of the instrument will represent the limits of the airway boundary? (Assume that the airway is 10 NM wide)",
    "options": [
      "6.0",
      "3.0",
      "4.5",
      "1.5"
    ],
    "correct": 3
  },
  {
    "question": "An aircraft is attempting to track 1860M on an airway defined by a VOR 80 nm away. The VOR indicates the aircraft position. With these indications the aircraft is on the ___ radial and ___ the airway.",
    "options": [
      "0010 outside",
      "1810 inside",
      "0010 inside",
      "1810 outside"
    ],
    "correct": 0
  },
  {
    "question": "An aircraft is on a heading of 100 degrees (m) from a VOR. To make the VOR/ILS deviation indicator needle centralise with the TO flag showing, the following bearing should be selected on the OBS:",
    "options": [
      "100 degrees",
      "110 degrees",
      "290 degrees",
      "280 degrees"
    ],
    "correct": 3
  },
  {
    "question": "The basic principle of operation of a standard VOR is by:",
    "options": [
      "phase comparison between a 108 Mhz reference signal and a 30 Hz variable signal",
      "phase difference between a frequency modulated reference signal and an amplitude modulated variable signal",
      "phase comparison between an amplitude modulated reference signal and a frequency modulated variable signal",
      "phase comparison between a 30 Hz reference signal and a 108 Mhz variable signal"
    ],
    "correct": 1
  },
  {
    "question": "An aircraft is tracking inbound to a VOR beacon on the 105 radial. The setting the pilot should put on the OBS and the CDI indications are:",
    "options": [
      "285, TO",
      "105, TO",
      "285, FROM",
      "105, FROM"
    ],
    "correct": 1
  },
  {
    "question": "An aircraft is on a VOR radial of 2350, heading 003o(M), and with the OBS set to 060. The correct indications are:",
    "options": [
      "TO: 1/2 Scale deflection to the left",
      "FROM: 1/2 Scale deflection to the left",
      "TO: 1/2 Scale deflection to the right",
      "FROM: 1/2 Scale deflection to the right"
    ],
    "correct": 0
  },
  {
    "question": "Using a VOR outside the DOC may result in interference from:",
    "options": [
      "other beacons",
      "other aircraft",
      "sky waves",
      "ground waves"
    ],
    "correct": 0
  },
  {
    "question": "The antenna polar diagram of a conventional VOR:",
    "options": [
      "is always directed towards the aircraft",
      "is like a figure of 8",
      "is a pencil beam",
      "Rotates at 30 revolutions per second"
    ],
    "correct": 3
  },
  {
    "question": "With reference to the VOR:",
    "options": [
      "Failure of the monitor will cause the beacon to cease its ident",
      "A typical VOR frequency is 118.15 Mhz",
      "The TO/FROM indicator shows whether the aircraft is heading towards or away from the beacon",
      "Wide coverage is obtained from only a few beacons"
    ],
    "correct": 0
  },
  {
    "question": "(Refer to figure 062-05) Refer to the diagram of a VOR/ILS deviation indicator. Assume that the indicator is set to define the centreline of an airway, that the aircraft is 90 nm from the VOR and inbound to the facility. At the time of observation the aircraft was located on radial:",
    "options": [
      "063o",
      "253o",
      "256o",
      "243o"
    ],
    "correct": 0
  },
  {
    "question": "If the compass providing information to the RMI suddenly gets a 20\u00b0 deviation:",
    "options": [
      "the magnetic track to the VOR station may be read on the compass card under the tip of the VOR needle",
      "the number of the received radial may still be read on the compass card under the tail of the VOR needle",
      "the relative bearing to the VOR, as observed on the RMI, will jump 20o",
      "all 3 answers are correct"
    ],
    "correct": 3
  },
  {
    "question": "Using a VOR beyond the limits of the DOC may result in:",
    "options": [
      "loss of signal due to line of sight limitations",
      "interference from other VORs operating on the same frequency",
      "sky wave contamination of the VOR signal",
      "scalloping errors"
    ],
    "correct": 1
  },
  {
    "question": "Using a 5 dot CDI, how many dots would show for an aircraft on the edge of an airway at 100 nm from the VOR beacon?",
    "options": [
      "5",
      "2.5",
      "1.5",
      "3"
    ],
    "correct": 2
  },
  {
    "question": "An Omni-bearing selector (OBS) shows full deflection to the left when within range of a serviceable VOR. What angular deviation are you from the selected radial?",
    "options": [
      "10o or more",
      "less than 10o",
      "1.5o or more",
      "2.5o or more"
    ],
    "correct": 0
  },
  {
    "question": "The letters QTX and adjacent symbol indicate a:",
    "options": [
      "VOR/DME",
      "TACAN",
      "VOR",
      "Airport"
    ],
    "correct": 0
  }
];
